today we're going to make chocolate
extract using caca nibs a little jar and
some
[Music]
booze extract is really expensive in the
stores good quality ones anyway you can
buy some absolute shite in um things
like bulk bar and
whatever and supermarkets all over the
world not necessarily just bulk bun good
stuff like nilson Macy there are other
brands out there that's just a brand
that I use not
affiliated it's super expensive some of
the flavors are quite difficult to make
but a lot of them are really simple so
that's what we're going to do we're
going to make chocolate extract you need
alcohol that's 40% ABV so 80% proof
we've got some vodka here that I
actually got free when I bought
this not a lot of that left um
rye whiskey vodka rum the rum's got to
be strong enough you know a lot of rum
sold in shops isn't particularly strong
anymore don't know why it really is that
simple we we're going to take our cow
nibs try and get an organic one because
they have a different flavor you get
this real artificial bitter aftertaste
with some kind of ultra processed ones
so what is a caca nib some people call
them coca nibs caca nibs I don't care
call them what you like they are are go
phone so you can see out close if you've
never seen a caca
nib it looks like
that hello caca nibs are when you take
I'll put some images on the screen nice
pictures of cacao beans and pods growing
on the trees certain parts of the
world once the the seeds are taken
outside of those cacao pods they are
fermented which creates the cocoa flavor
they are then dried for a set period of
time then they are dehusked so the outer
casing is removed and what is left is a
super intense chocolate flavor
Bean at that stage you can take those
beans and crush them or break them into
this that that's it that's all that is
that's what a cacao nib or a cocoa nib
is it's the
unprocessed cacao bean unprocessed
meaning it hasn't been turned into
something else
but we want to take the flavor out of
those and put them into some kind of
alcohol this isn't enough to fill in
here but what we're going to
do is
combine the two we're going to put that
in there smells of absolutely nothing
and we're going to top that off with
some of the Rye Whiskey I'm not going to
drink any because it
is 10 12 in the
afternoon if it was 8:00 at night then
yes but so what we've got there how much
is in there how big is this it is 118 ml
or 4 oz so we're kind of just over
halfway
probably probably like 3 fths and all
we're going to do now is just get
our cacao nibs in there we want to get a
good few in there because we want this
to be really strong this is going to
give us about 50 to 75 M worth of
chocolate
extract lid
on quick Shake the shake just makes sure
that there's none stuck to anything not
really essential and it will
automatically start to go a muddy color
that is it we're going to leave that out
on the counter for about 3 to four weeks
and after a month or two this has been
in the cupboard I think for 2 months you
are left with a seriously
intense chocolate extract you can keep
those cacao nibs in in there if you want
or you can strain them out and be left
with just the liquor but either way caca
nibs will eventually go off in there so
I personally would drain those out and
decant that liquor and then start
another one and just keep building up
because you can use this in anything you
can use this in hot chocolate you can
use this in ice cream you can use this
in baking you can use this in Savory
dishes as well cacao or pure chocolate
has been used in Savory dishes for
centuries so experiment with this if you
want to see how to make extracts natural
extracts of pretty much anything let me
know in the comments don't forget to
like And subscribe hit the like button
as well and I will see you next time
[Music]